<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aman Pratap Singh</title>
    <link>https://blog.amanps.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aman Pratap Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 04:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.amanps.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflections at 25</title>
      <link>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2023-06-24-reflections-at-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 04:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2023-06-24-reflections-at-25/</guid>
      <description>It’s June, and the mango season. I have just closed the lid of my work laptop after a typical workday. While pondering what to do with the couple of spare hours before dinner, here I am trying to scribble something again on this long forgotten blog feed.
I completed 25 years of life this month and as my me-only solitude whatsapp chatgroup is brimming with my cold shower thoughts journal-ish entries, I am attempting this writing to stitch these thoughts in a blog (after a long break of 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Year log</title>
      <link>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2021-01-01-2020-year-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 04:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2021-01-01-2020-year-log/</guid>
      <description>I still remember the night of 31st December 2019. College was scheduled to reopen from 1st January for Spring Semester. I was flying from New Delhi to Bhubaneswar after the winter break. Spent the beginning of new year in air, reached my college’s hostel at around 1:30 AM. Few of floormates were already there and they had big plans for the night. What happened after that is hazy in the memory, the only thing I remember is I woke in evening of 1st Jan and missed the semester registration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The semester of Hackathons</title>
      <link>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2019-03-10-the-semester-of-hackathons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 04:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2019-03-10-the-semester-of-hackathons/</guid>
      <description>Seeing the Hackathon related posts and conversations on Twitter and Reddit, I always had a desire to attend a Hackathon before my college ends. Finally this spring semester I got the chance to attend not just one but two hackathons. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my experience of participating in Inter IIT Tech Meet Coding Hackathon 2018 and winning Smart India Hackathon 2019.
Inter IIT Tech Meet Coding Hackathon Inter IIT Tech Meet is an annual event where all IITs compete in various technical competitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC with CERN-HSF (Part-2)</title>
      <link>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2018-08-21-gsoc-with-cern-hsf-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 04:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2018-08-21-gsoc-with-cern-hsf-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Hello, I’m Aman, GSoC 2018 student under CERN-HSF. Last month, I wrote about my Project and the work I did in the first month of the GSoC coding period. This post summarises the work I did in the last two months of the GSoC coding period and what I achieved overall in the summer.
The second Coding Phase In the second coding phase, I mostly worked on designing and implementing the Jobs tab in Jupyter tree view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC with CERN-HSF (Part-1)</title>
      <link>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2018-06-09-gsoc-with-cern-hsf-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 04:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2018-06-09-gsoc-with-cern-hsf-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I have been selected in Google Summer of Code 2018 under CERN-HSF umbrella organisation. My project is co-mentored by HEP Software Foundation and Imperial College, London.
This was the first time I applied for GSoC. It was my dream from the freshman year and I started preparing for it from a long time ago. I started writing code for fun, published it on Github, contributed to multiple open source projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chilika Lake : The Best of Odisha</title>
      <link>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2018-03-31-chilka-lake-the-best-of-odisha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 04:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2018-03-31-chilka-lake-the-best-of-odisha/</guid>
      <description>So it had been one and a half year since I landed in Odisha, The soul of Incredible India and I hadn’t explored any of Odisha’s great landscapes except a short trip to Udaygiri and Khandagiri, so to consume the wanderlust generated over three semesters, We (I and my 9 other friends) decided to had a detour from our monotonous college life and visit Chilika Lake, Asia’s largest brackish water lagoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Scrapping with Python</title>
      <link>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2017-12-15-web-scrapping-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 13:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2017-12-15-web-scrapping-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Internet has superabundant information and knowledge but to extract that knowledge in organised, scalable and systemetic way for data analysis and other research purpose is known as Web Scrapping.
Web Scrapping automatically extracts the data from a particular website and present it in user desired form. We can scrap many things from the web like Stock updates, Price of any product from Amazon. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll scrap news updates from my college&amp;rsquo;s website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Competitive Programming Environment</title>
      <link>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2017-06-25-setting-up-competitive-programming-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 13:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2017-06-25-setting-up-competitive-programming-environment/</guid>
      <description>1. Chosing an Operating System Almost every beginner use Windows but the OS preferred by veteran developers and programmers is certainly Linux as it provide a better coding experience and plethora of customization opportunities.
The following article describe why you should consider using Linux:
7 Superb Reasons Why You Should Use Linux For Programming
Chosing a Linux Distro The another great thing about Linux is that there are plenty of distros available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2017-06-05-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 16:16:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.amanps.xyz/posts/2017-06-05-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Bonjour! So after 3 countiguous hours, I&amp;rsquo;m finally done with setting up this blog with Jekyll. At first glance it was perplexing but as I dived deep into documentation of Jekyll everything sorted out.
What is Jekyll ? Quoting from Jekyll Documentation:
Jekyll is a simple, blog-aware, static site generator. It takes a template directory containing raw text files in various formats, runs it through a converter (like Markdown) and our Liquid renderer, and spits out a complete, ready-to-publish static website suitable for serving with your favorite web server.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
